Hi, it's me, Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut.
原作者名：Everyday Astronaut
视频来源：youtu.be/UEO77UEFGT4
原视频发布日期：20200725
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
嗨 我是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
Remember that time when NASA sent an SUV sized rover to the surface of Mars.
还记得那次NASA派了一辆SUV大小的漫游车去火星表面吗？
Yeah. You might remember the Curiosity rover and perhaps you recall its daring touchdown sequence,
是的 你可能还记得好奇号 漫游车 也许你还记得它那大胆的着陆过程
which utilized a rocket powered sky crane.
其中利用了火箭动力的天空起重机
Whether or not you remember the Curiosity rover, I do have some great news.
不管你是否还记得好奇号漫游车 我都有些好消息
NASA's about to do it again,
NASA还要再送个漫游车上去
only as you would hope they've made some awesome improvements,
只不过这次你会希望他们做了一些了不起的改进
including a part of the mission that I'm super excited for
其中一部分任务让我感到十分兴奋
because they're going to be flying a drone around in the atmosphere of Mars.
因为他们要让无人机到火星的大气层里飞行
So in today's video, let's do an overview of this new Mars rover named Perseverance,
所以在今天的视频中 让我们简单介绍下毅力号 这个新火星车
also known as the Mars 2020 mission.
又称2020火星任务
The rocket that'll take it to Mars, the timeline, the landing sequence,
(包括)将把它送上火星的火箭 (事件的)时间线 着陆时序
and then we'll compare it alongside the Curiosity rover
然后我们会把它和好奇号 漫游车进行比较
to see what's actually changed and what stayed the same,
来看看哪些变了哪些没变
including the instrumentation and the missions.
这之中包括设备和任务的部分
And we'll even hear from JPL engineer Bobak Ferdowsi
我们甚至会听到JPL工程师Bobak Ferdowsi的谈话
about what he's most excited for with this awesome new Mars rover.
关于这个不错的新火星车 他所感到兴奋的部分是哪些地方
Okay. Let's get started.
好吧 我们开始吧
-  [任务控制]三 二 一
- [Mission Control] Three, two, one,
起飞
and liftoff!
-  [尼尔]这是对人类的一小步
- [Neil] That's one small step for man.
-  [任务控制]这是休斯敦和一号测试的通信
- [Mission Control] That's Houston contact for the test one.
NASA's Curiosity rover has been a home run flagship NASA mission,
NASA的好奇号 漫游车一直是NASA的全垒打级别的旗舰任务
and its produced an incredible amount of data since it landed on Mars all the way back on August 6, 2012,
自2012年8月6日登陆火星以来 它产生了大量的数据
and those eight years since doing science on the surface of Mars,
而在火星表面做科学工作的这八年
it found evidence of previous liquid water.
它发现了以前存在液态水的证据
It discovered Mars has had the right chemistry to support living microbes,
它发现火星有合适的化学成分来支持活的微生物
having discovered sulfur, nitrogen, oxygen, phosphorus, and carbon,
发现了硫 氮 氧 磷和碳
all the key ingredients that make life.
所有组成生命的关键成分
To further that note of potential life,
为了进一步挖掘潜在的生命的记录
it found organic carbon molecules, active methane in the atmosphere,
它发现有机碳分子 以及大气中周期性变动的甲烷比例
and even found out that Mars once had a thicker atmosphere and more water.
甚至发现火星曾经有更厚的大气层和更多的水
It's also helped lay the foundation for future human missions to Mars by precisely measuring the radiation,
它还通过精确测量辐射 为未来载人火星任务奠定了基础
finding that Mars is radiation environment is too high for human presence, if not shielded.
发现火星的辐射环境对人类来说太高了 需要一定的辐射屏蔽
So with all this awesome stuff,
所以有了这些厉害的东西
being tested and measured and discovered it raises the question,
在这样的测试 测量 发现之后 它提出了一个问题
what else is there to do?
还有什么可做的？
I mean, what's Perseverance going to do that Curiosity didn't do.
我是说毅力号 能做 而好奇号 却没做的那些
They kind of look the same don't they?
它们看起来很像 不是吗？
Well, as you can probably guess there's still a ton of science to be done
你可能也猜到了 还有很多科学工作要做呢
and Perseverance is really going to be kicking it up a notch.
而毅力号 真的能把它提高一个水平
So let's start off by doing an overview of the mission timeline.
所以 我们先来简单介绍下任务时间表
Then we'll go into the details of the hardware and compare those to Curiosity.
然后我们将进入设备的细节 并将其与好奇号 进行比较
And since this is a pretty long video, we've got timestamps here on the screen.
因为这是一个很长的视频 我会把时间戳放在屏幕这儿
02:50 发射 / 运输    05:30 进入 / 下降段 / 着陆时序
09:00 毅力号 对比好奇号    22:00 JPL工程师Bobak Ferdowsi
22:45 总结
The play bar on YouTube is actually divided into the sections.
YouTube上的进度条实际上被分成了几个部分
And we have an article version with sources in the description as well.
而且我们还有一个带有来源的文章版 放在视频简介中了
发射 / 运输
Perseverance is scheduled to lift off during the 2020 launch window,
毅力号 计划在2020年发射窗口期间升空
which is from the middle of July to the middle of August.
窗口期从七月中旬开始 持续到八月中旬
If you're watching this about August 15th, 2020,
如果你在2020年8月15日左右看到这个视频
and it hasn't taken off, it means the next opportunity to launch isn't until August, 2022.
而它还没有起飞 这意味着下一次发射的机会要等到2022年8月
Although as of the making of this video,
虽然截止到这段视频的制作
NASA is looking into potentially launching a little bit after August 15th as a contingency option,
NASA正在研究有可能在8月15日之后一点时间进行发射来作为应急方案
but regardless of when they actually end up launching they'll land on Mars at the exact same time and date,
但不管何时发射 它们都会在轨道力学的作用下 于相同的时间和日期着陆火星
February 18th, 2021 at 3:30 PM Eastern, thanks to orbital mechanics.
抵达的时间也就是2021年2月19日04:30(UTC+8)
Now just like the Curiosity rover, Perseverance will be heading to Mars,
那么就像好奇号 漫游车一样 毅力号 将前往火星
riding the Atlas 5 rocket in almost its most powerful configuration,
乘坐几乎是最高配型号的宇宙神5号火箭
which is the 541 meaning
也就是宇宙神V 541
it's going to have a 5m fairing, 4 solid rocket motors and a single RL-10 centaur upper stage engine.
这个型号有5米长的整流罩 4台固体火箭发动机和1台RL-10半人马上面级发动机
It's going to take all that power of United launch Alliance's workhorse rocket to get the heavy Perseverance,
这将需要联合发射联盟的这枚主力火箭的所有动力来让沉重的毅力号
the 105 million kilometers to Mars.
经过1.05亿公里的里程到达火星
Well actually to be pedantic,
其实说得考究一点
the distance the rover will actually travel to get to Mars is more like 497 million kilometers.
漫游车到达火星的实际距离更像是4.97亿公里
Because as those of you who have played Kerbal Space Program might know
因为玩过坎巴拉太空计划的人可能都知道
to get to Mars, you don't travel in a straight line when the two planets are closest to each other.
要想去火星 不会按照两个星球最近的直线轨迹来进行机动
你实际上是提高了你围绕太阳的轨道
You actually raise your orbit around the sun.
所以这条轨道要与火星的轨道相交并且拦截到火星
So it intersects with Mars is orbit and you need to intercept Mars
在那个确切的时间点到达那个确切的地点时
when it gets to that exact point at that exact time.
After its long seven month journey, Perseverance will touch down on the Martian surface in February, 2021.
在经历了七个月的漫长旅程后 毅力号 将于2021年2月在火星表面着陆
it'll land at the Jezero crater location chosen for its possibility of harboring life in the past.
它将降落在Jezero陨石坑的位置 之所以选择它是因为过去的生命可能栖息于此
It's believed that the crater was at one point flooded with water,
据信 这个陨石坑曾一度被水淹没
which would have allowed for the presence of life in ancient times.
而这将使远古时代的生命得以存在
The EDLS or the entry descent and landing system will contain a new technology called terrain relative navigation.
EDLS或者说进入下降和着陆系统将包含一种称为相对地形导航的新技术
This will allow a computer to scan the terrain during descent and then compare it to an orbital map,
这将使计算机能够在下降过程中扫描地形 然后将其与轨道上拍摄的地图进行比较
and it will be able to divert to a safer landing zone if necessary.
并在必要时转移到更安全的着陆区
Another feature known as the range trigger will determine when the parachute should be open,
另一个被称为距离触发器的功能 其将决定何时该打开降落伞
allowing the rover to land much closer to points of scientific interest,
使漫游车能够在更接近有利于科学研究的地方着陆
which ends up saving valuable time that otherwise be spent just slowly driving around on Mars.
这最终节省了宝贵的时间 否则就只能在火星上慢慢开过去了
So here's how that sequence of events will actually occur.
下面是这一连串事件的实际发生过程
This might all sound pretty familiar if you've seen Curiosity's landing sequence
如果你看过好奇号 的着陆时序 这听起来可能很熟悉
that also features the rocket powered sky-crane.
同样也有火箭动力的天空起重机
进入 / 下降段 / 着陆时序
At entry minus 10 minutes, the cruise stage separates and burns up in the Martian atmosphere.
在进入前10分钟 巡航级分离 并在火星大气层中烧毁
At entry plus zero minutes, that's of course, when the craft will begin to enter the Martian atmosphere.
在进入时刻 那当然是 航天器开始进入火星大气层的时候
Entry plus 80 seconds, the heat shield experiences, the maximum amount of heating roughly 2100 degrees Celsius.
在进入后80秒时 隔热板将经历最大加热量 达到约为2100摄氏度
At entry plus 90 seconds, the craft experiences, the maximum deceleration
在进入后90秒时 航天器经历了最大的减速度
slowing down from 21,200 kilometers an hour to just 1600 kilometers an hour and only two and a half minutes.
从每小时21200公里减速到每小时只有1600公里 只用了两分半钟
At E plus 240 seconds, at an altitude of around nine to 13 kilometers, the parachute deploys.
在进入后240秒时 在约9至13公里的高度 降落伞展开
At E plus 260 seconds shortly after, the heat shield separates and falls to the Martian surface,
在进入后260秒后不久 隔热板分离 落到火星表面
the radar ground system will activate and begin scanning the Martian surface for a suitable touchdown zone.
雷达地面系统将启动并开始扫描火星表面 寻找合适的着陆区
At around E plus 350 seconds, the back shell separates
在进入后350秒左右时 后壳分离
and the rover begins a brief free fall before the landing motors ignite.
在着陆发动机点火前 漫游车开始短暂的自由落体
This is definitely the maximum pucker moment
这绝对是最紧张的时刻
At an altitude of just 21 meters, the rover separates from the landing stage
在只有21米的高度 探测器与着陆级分离
and is gently lowered to the ground on three nylon ropes.
并由三根尼龙绳缓缓降到地面
At this point, the craft has slowed down to just 2.7 kilometers an hour.
此时 飞行器的速度已经减慢到2.7km/h
Finally, the rover touches down on the surface
最后 漫游车降落在地表上
and the landing stage that sky crane will fly away before it crashes into the surface.
而着陆级 天空起重机将在坠入火星表面之前飞走
And this will officially begin Perseverance its mission on the surface of Mars.
而这将正式开始毅力号 在火星表面的任务
Now, if you're anything like me,
现在 如果你和我一样
maybe you've always wondered how can that sky crane make any sense?
也许你一直在想 那个天空起重机到底咋回事儿？
It seems like there's a lot of extra parts,
好像有很多多余的零件
extra systems dangling from this rope and all this stuff.
额外的系统吊在这根绳子上 等等
It seems like a lot more trouble than it's worth.
看起来似乎弊大于利
Why don't they just put the rover on top of the sky-crane and just land it like normal and drive off the top.
为什么不把漫游车放在天空起重机的顶部 像平常一样降落 然后漫游车从顶部开走
Wouldn't that be a lot it's easier and lighter?
那不是更容易更轻巧吗？
Well, to answer that there's really two main reasons.
要回答这个问题 有两个主要原因
And the first one is, when you have something as heavy as Perseverance,
第一个原因是 当你有像毅力号 这么重的东西时
which is about a metric ton landing propulsively
也就是将近一公吨质量的反推着陆
you can't have the rocket engines firing too close to the ground.
你不能让火箭发动机离地面太近
You'll basically make a crater, which is the same reason
否则会吹出一个大坑 也是如此
why we're seeing the lunar Lander version of Starship have auxiliary landing engines up really high.
月球着陆器版Starship的辅助着陆引擎处在非常高的位置
So if you did put the rover on top of it
所以 如果你真的把月球车放在上面的话
and you wanted to make sure those rockets weren't too close to the ground,
还要确保这些火箭不会离地面太近
you'd have to put it on like giant stilts or giant landing legs and those weigh a lot.
你就必须把它放在像巨大的高跷或着陆腿上 那就重了很多
And then now your rover's on top of a giant thing with landing legs and stilts,
然后现在你的漫游车呆在这样一个庞然大物的顶部 它有着着陆腿或者说高跷
and to drive it off, you'd have to have this ramp or some kind of system then to get it off of that.
要想把它开走 你必须有个坡道 或某种系统 然后把它从上面弄下来
And now you just added even more weight and complexity and made it pretty, pretty risky, honestly.
而现在 实话说 你只是增加了更多的重量和复杂度 并且让它变得非常非常危险
And the other reason is actually for control.
另一个原因其实是为了控制
It's a lot easier to let the crane just kind of hover roughly above the surface
让起重机在表面上盘旋会容易得多
and then use a tether that has some slack in it.
然后用一根有点儿松的绳子
So there's a lot of wiggle room there.
所以 这会有很多的回旋余地
You basically to start lowering the rover until it touches the ground.
一开始 基本上只要把漫游车降下来 直到它接触到地面
Once it touches the ground,
一旦它接触到地面
they cut those tethers and the sky crane just flies away.
就剪断绳索 然后天空起重机就飞走了
So it doesn't need to get down perfectly and just land very, very, very gently.
所以它不需要完美地降落 只需要非常轻柔地降落
So again, this all sounds like deja vu with Curiosity having done quite literally all of this stuff,
所以 这一切听起来就像已经做过这些事儿的好奇号 一样
proving out this entire system and all the wacky landing sequences.
而好奇号 的成功着陆证明了这整个系统和所有古怪的降落时序的可行性
So let's actually compare these two rovers side-by-side and then we'll see what's new and note-worthy.
那么 我们实际将这两台漫游车并排比较一下 然后再看看有什么新的值得注意的地方
毅力号 对比好奇号
Well, to begin,
好吧 开始吧
both rovers are virtually identical designs with Perseverance actually using some of Curiosity's backup parts.
两辆漫游车的设计几乎完全相同 毅力号 实际上使用了好奇号 的一些备用零件
Each rover is 2.9 meters wide, 2.7 meters long, and 2.2 meters tall.
每个漫游车宽2.9米 长2.7米 高2.2米
It's easy to forget just how big these rovers are.
很容易让人忘记这些漫游车有多大
I mean, they're almost the size of a small SUV.
我的意思是 它们几乎和一辆小型SUV一样大
Although they're nearly identical in size,
虽然它们的大小几乎一样
Perseverance will be heavier, weighing in at 1050 kilograms versus Curiosity's 899 kilograms.
毅力号会更重 重达1050kg 而好奇号的重量为899kg
So let's take a look at the changes that make Perseverance heavier.
那么我们来看看是哪些变化让毅力号 变得更重
Both rovers utilize the same body,
两款漫游车都使用了相同的车体
which is called the WEB or the warm electronics box.
这就是所谓的WEB或温暖的电子箱
It's this strong outer layer that protects the computers and the electronics
就是这层坚固的外层 保护着电脑和电子产品
and keeps them temperature controlled
并使其温度得到控制
On top of the web or the deck is the large mast that houses the main cameras,
在网络或甲板的顶部是大型桅杆 里面有主要的摄像头
which are the super cam and the Mast Cam Z.
即超级相机和桅杆相机Z
Then there's the Mars environmental dynamic analyzer or known as MEDA,
还有就是火星环境动态分析仪 也就是所谓的MEDA
which is basically a little weather station.
这基本上是一个小气象站
And on the bottom of Perseverance is a sample collecting system.
而在毅力号 的底部是一个样本收集系统
Now this is one of the biggest upgrades for Perseverance.
这是毅力号 最大的升级之一
Perseverance will collect rock cores for future study.
毅力号 将为未来的研究收集岩芯
Now this is a little confusing to me because the samples will just be stored,
这让我有点困惑 因为样本将被储存起来
ready for someone or something else to pick them up and return them for further analysis.
准备好让别人或其他东西来取走它们 并将它们送回做进一步分析
But if something else comes along to grab these samples,
但如果需要别的东西来拿走这些样品
why can't that thing just drill its own core samples?!
为什么那东西不能自己钻取钻心样本呢？
Isn't that kind of trivial compared to getting to Mars?
比起把它带去火星 这是不是有点小题大做？
I mean, isn't it actually kind of hard to have to retrace Perseverance's steps
我是指 要重走毅力号 的道路 是不是真的有点难？
and grab all of its cores instead of just drilling its own samples itself?
并抓取之前采集过的所有样本 而不只是自己钻探样本？
Well, first off storing samples before any more human interference or future Mars missions land on the planet
好吧 在有人类干扰或者未来火星任务降落之前 先把样品储存起来
ensures clean samples before any potential contamination.
可以确保样品干净 不受之后任何潜在的污染
So that's a good thing, but second, it also saves the weight of the heavy drill and containment system
所以这是件好事 但其次 它也节省了沉重的钻头的重量和保存容器
from being required on a future rover.
这样未来的漫游车就不需要这些设备了
Perseverance, will collect at least 20 samples.
毅力号 将至少收集20个样本
It has 43 sample collecting containers and five witness tubes.
它有43个样本收集容器和5个见证管
So what they're going to do is they'll open up these witness tubes during drilling sessions
所以他们要做的就是在钻探过程中打开这些见证管子
that are preloaded with materials that can capture molecular and particle contaminants.
预装了能够捕获分子和颗粒污染物的材料
In other words, these witness tubes will capture gases that may be released or out gas from the rover itself,
换言之 这些见证管将捕获可能从漫游器本身释放或排出的气体
chemical remanence from the landing system
或者着陆系统的化学残留物
or any other earthly organic or inorganic material that may have somehow made its way to Mars.
或其他可能以某种方式进入火星的地球有机或无机物质
This ensures that there's a control to observe later on.
这就确保了以后有一个可以观察的对照
So when they're looking at samples,
所以当他们在观察样品的时候
they can cross reference the witness tubes
他们可以交叉参考见证管
and that'll let them know whether or not the materials actually from the sample or from the rover,
那会让他们知道这些材料是来自样品还是来自漫游车
or potentially even from Earth.
甚至有可能来自地球
The rover stores the tubes under its belly on a carousel.
漫游车将管子存放在腹部的转盘上
And there's a small robot arm that hands, the sample tubes off to the main arm,
有一个小型机械臂将样品管送到主臂上
It's kind of like a lab assistant to the big arm, which is kind of cool.
这有点像主臂的实验室助手 挺酷的
Then depending on what NASA ends up wanting to do,
然后根据NASA最终想要做的事情
it'll do a deposit of the samples all at once
它将一次完成样品的存放
or in a few strategic places for future sample collection and return.
或放在一些合适的地方 并为将来的样本收集和返回做准备
There's even already plans in the works with ESA and NASA to send another rover down
甚至已经有计划要让欧空局和NASA合作 将另一个漫游车送过去
that will have a mini rocket on it, and basically be a small launch pad.
那上面会有一个迷你火箭 基本上就是一个小型发射台
And that's of course possible because Mars has a lot lower gravity as my shirt will tell me
当然 这也是可能的 因为火星上的重力要低得多 我的衣服会告诉我的
and a lower atmosphere, which shirt will also tell me.
和较低的大气层 我的衣服也说了
So it takes a lot smaller rocket to get something from Mars into Mars orbit,
所以想要把火星上的东西送入火星轨道 然后再回到地球
and then back to Earth than it would to get something from Earth to Mars.
一枚小很多的火箭就足够了 比起从地球上到火星要容易得多
Okay. So they'll take this new rover, drive it over to a sample.
好吧 所以通过这个新的漫游车 开到样本的位置附近
They'll stick that sample on this little rocket they'll launch that rocket into Mars orbit,
然后把样本放在小火箭上 再把小火箭发射到火星轨道上
and then it will likely rendezvous with another probe that will end up pushing it all the way to Earth.
然后它很可能会与另一个探测器交会 最终将它一路带到地球
Now these plans change and they won't happen until at least 2028.
现在这些计划改变了 它们至少要到2028年才会发生
So we won't be getting any sense sample returns until the 2030s at best.
所以我们最多要到2030年代才能得到返回的样本
And this feels like a pretty hail Mary stretch of events to have to work perfectly.
应该是指Rose Mary Stretch
而这感觉就像一个漂亮的Mary伸展那样 必须完美地工作
It almost makes me wonder if humans will just end up collecting those samples themselves
这几乎让我怀疑人们是否会自己收集这些样本
or just bringing their own drills and observing Mars right there on a Martian base or something,
或者干脆自己带着钻头 就在火星基地上观察火星什么的
or bringing them back to earth with them.
或将他们一起带回地球
But although it's definitely a cool way
虽然这绝对是一个很酷的方式
and an important thing to preserve samples before any human presence.
以及在任何人类登火之前保存样本的重要事情
Okay so back to Perseverance and that big arm on the front,
好了 回到毅力号 和它前面的那只大手臂
it's been massively upgraded compared to Curiosity.
与好奇号 相比 它被大幅升级了
It has a new hand or a turret full of new science tools.
它有一个新手或者说炮塔 其上充满了新的科学工具
It also has an updated coring drill and two science instruments alongside a color camera
它还有一个更新的岩心钻和两个科学仪器 以及一个彩色摄像机
for closeups surface inspections and those awesome selfies like Curiosity has taken.
用于近距离的表面检查 以及像好奇号 那样拍出的那些超赞的自拍
Learning from the issues with Curiosity,
从 好奇号 的问题中学习
the teams at NASA have made some significant changes
NASA的团队已经做出了一些重大的改变
that should extend the rover's lifespan and allow it to conduct even more science.
这应该会延长漫游车的寿命 让它能进行更多的科学活动
The biggest change is probably the wheels which have been redesigned to have a larger diameter
最大的变化可能是轮子 经过重新设计 它的直径更大了
and a smaller tread width than Curiosity's wheels.
而胎面花纹更密
These new wheels should prevent Perseverance from getting stuck in the Martian sand, as Curiosity did in 2014.
这些新轮子应该可以防止毅力号 像2014年好奇号 那样卡在火星沙地里
Perseverance also has a new cutting edge instrument suite using its x-ray spectrometer and UV laser.
毅力号 还有一个新的尖端仪器套件 使用它的X射线光谱仪和紫外激光器
It'll scan the Martian surface at an even finer scale than ever before, to search for evidence of Martian life.
它将以比以往更精细的尺度扫描火星表面 以寻找火星生命的证据
Perhaps one of the upgrades that I'm most excited for is its huge upgrade to cameras.
也许我最兴奋的升级之一是它对相机的巨大升级
Perseverance will carry a remarkable 23 cameras to the surface.
毅力号 将携带惊人的23台相机前往火星
Including some that will film the final descent the Martian atmosphere, capturing all inspiring footage,
有些相机将拍摄在火星大气层中进行最终下降段的视频 捕捉所有令人振奋的镜头
as the craft drifts down towards the Martian surface.
最终下降段也就是航天器组合体正往火星表面飘下的时候
The new cameras will also be higher resolution.
新相机的分辨率也将更高
While Curiosity's best camera was only about two megapixels.
而好奇号 最好的相机只有200万像素左右
The camera on board will capture 20 megapixel full color images.
新相机将拍摄2000万像素的全彩图像
Now I know that this might not seem like the most scientifically valuable thing,
那么我知道 这可能看起来不是最有科学价值的东西
but I think it's one of the most important pieces of the mission
但我认为这是任务中最重要的部分之一
that help raise the public's interest and help all of us get a sense of actually being there.
有助于提高公众的兴趣 并提供一种身临其境的感觉
After all, Public interest is a big part of these flagship NASA missions.
毕竟 公众的兴趣是NASA这些旗舰任务的重要组成部分
And this has a few fun elements that you may have actually been a part of.
而你可能已经参与到其中一些有趣的元素当中了
Perseverance will be carrying 10.9 million names on board, three thumbnail sized Silicon chips.
毅力号 将携带1090万个名字上箭 它们被存储在三个拇指甲大小的硅芯片
Maybe your name's on it.
也许你的名字就在上面
There's also a tribute plate to the medical community and another with an image of earth Mars and the sun.
还有一个向医学界致敬的牌子 而另一个是地球火星和太阳的图像
And the rover was named Perseverance by Alex Mather
还有就是 这辆漫游车被Alex Mather命名为毅力
who won a  K-12 public naming contest with 28,000 entries.
这个名字从义务教育学生参与的公众命名比赛中的28000个名字中脱颖而出
I love seeing the public gets so involved in these missions,
我喜欢看到公众如此参与这些任务当中
but to expand on the public experience, Perseverance will also carry two microphones,
但为了扩大公众体验 毅力号 还将携带两个麦克风
which will capture the sound of Mars during the landing as well as on the surface.
它将捕捉到在火星着陆过程以及火星表面的声音
I can't wait for all the footage to roll in.
我迫不及待地想看到所有的镜头
Beautiful descent footage with real sound, awesome high resolution images.
美丽的降落镜头伴随着真实的声音以及令人赞叹的高分辨率图像
I mean, Perseverance would be bringing Mars to us better than ever before.
我是指毅力号 会比以往都更好地把火星带到我们面前
Perseverance's power system will basically be the same thing as Curiosity,
毅力号 的动力系统基本上会和好奇号一样
which has proven to be incredibly reliable.
而这已被证明是非常可靠的
It's a 45 kilogram radioisotopic thermal electric generator or an RTG
这是一个45kg重的放射性同位素热电机或称RTG
that converts the heat of radioactive decay of plutonium into electricity.
它将钚的放射性衰变的热量转化为电能
Along with the RTG, there's also pair of lithium ion batteries to help handle peak demands
除了RTG之外 还有一对锂离子电池来帮助处理用电高峰
or times when the rover is using more energy than the RTG produces.
也就是当漫游车使用的能量超过RTG产生的能量时
The RTG is designed to last 14 years,
RTG的设计寿命为14年
which is fine beyond the plan mission duration of 1.5 Mars years or three earth years.
这比计划中的1.5个火星年或3个地球年的任务期限都要强很多
This is a pretty typical JPL thing to over-engineer
这是一个非常典型的进行了过度设计的JPL产品
and we're definitely thankful when it comes to rovers like Curiosity and Perseverance.
我们肯定要感谢把过度设计的理念用在像好奇号 和毅力号 这样的漫游车上
I guess, Opportunity also who have exceeded all expectations of life duration.
为避免歧义，说明下机遇号并没有RTG，Tim这里只是说冗余性设计的好处
我想 机遇号 的寿命(也因此)超出了所有人的预料
I mean, they just keep on going!
我是指 机遇号 和好奇号 就像这样不停地走了下去
Fun side note here about the RTG.
还有一个关于RTG的有趣的事情
This will be the first mission to launch from the US utilizing an RTG
在美国使用RTG发射的任务当中
that won't require the president to directly approve the launch.
这是第一次不会要求总统直接批准的
The permissions have changed allowing NASA administrators to approve the launch.
权限已经改变 现在允许NASA局长来批准发射
So our good friend, Jim Bridenstine will give his thumbs up and it'll be launch time.
所以我们的好朋友 Jim Bridenstine将会批准发射
Another thing that's just like Curiosity, Perseverance, will use three forms of communications.
另一个和好奇号 一样的东西 毅力号 将使用三种通信形式
An ultra high frequency antenna with data transmission of up to two megabits per second,
一根超高频天线 数据传输速度高达2Mbps
from the rover to the relay link.
(这个速度是指)从漫游车到中继链路
Then there's the X-band high gain antenna,
然后是X波段高增益天线
which has a steerable beam that can transmit data directly to earth at 160 to 500 bits per second.
它有一个可转向的波束 可以以160bit/s-500bit/s的速度直接向地球传输数据
And lastly, there's an X band, low gain antenna,
最后 还有一个X波段 低增益天线
which is primarily for receiving signals and can only transfer 10 bits per second.
主要用于接收信号 只有10bit/s的速度
So you really don't want to use this for any images or anything like that.
所以你真的不想用它来传任何图像之类的东西
Another fun upgrade and experiment that's going to be on Perseverance,
另一个有趣的升级和实验 要在毅力号 上进行了
and something that's going to be really useful for future crewed missions to Mars
这也是对未来火星载人任务非常有用的东西
will be the first attempts at producing oxygen on the surface of Mars
那就是首次尝试在火星表面生产氧气
using in-situ resource utilization with an awesome experiment called MOXIE.
通过MOXIE这个很棒的利用原位资源的技术进行的实验
Although Mars has an atmosphere, it's very thin as you can read on my shirt here again,
虽然火星有大气层 但它非常稀薄 你又可以在我这里的衣服上读到
only about 1% as dense as Earth
密度仅为地球的1%
and of that 1% density, carbon dioxide makes up around 96% of the gas in Mars' atmosphere.
而在这1%的密度中 二氧化碳约占火星大气中气体的96%
Oxygen = 氧气， Nitrogen = 氮气
Carbon Dioxide = 二氧化碳， Trace Gases = 微量气体
Oxygen is only 0.174% compared to the 21% in Earth's much thicker atmosphere.
氧气只占0.174% 而在更为浓厚的地球大气中的占比则为21%
Getting really pedantic here if you factor in the partial pressures of earth and Mars,
如果考虑到地球和火星的分压 这里就变得非常考究了
take the average temperature into consideration and convert to moles,
考虑到平均温度并将其转换为摩尔
taking a breath on Mars, you'd only inhale about 0.0071% as much oxygen as you would at sea level on earth.
在火星上吸一口气 你只相当于吸入约0.0071%的地球海平面的氧气
Or in other words, there's about 14,000 times more oxygen per liter on Earth than on the surface of Mars.
或者换句话说 地球上每升的氧气含量是火星表面的14000倍
So if humans are going to live on Mars, we've got to make oxygen.
所以 如果人类要在火星上生活 就必须制造氧气
And maybe just as importantly, if these humans are to return home,
也许同样重要的是 如果这些人要回家的话
they'll need oxygen for their rocket.
他们的火箭需要氧气
So figuring out how to make oxygen out of the carbon dioxide in the atmosphere of Mars is vital.
所以想办法用火星大气中的二氧化碳制造氧气是至关重要的
And as if all of this wasn't just enough, awesome upgrades,
如果这一切还不够的话 还有更棒的升级
Perseverance has one more incredible trick up its sleeve, or should I say under its belly.
trick up one's sleeve = 锦囊妙计，这里是双关了
毅力号 的袖子里还有一个不可思议的把戏 或者我该说这是在它的肚子下面
Perseverance will not be flying alone.
毅力号 并不孤单
It'll be joined by a small drone helicopter named Ingenuity.
一架名为机智号 的小型无人直升机将陪伴它
Ingenuity will demonstrate the possibility of flight on Mars
机智号 将验证在火星上飞行的可能性
and will provide engineers on Earth with aerial images to better plan routes for Perseverance.
并将为地球上的工程师提供航空图像 以便更好地规划毅力号 的路线
Because of its proximity to the surface,
由于它接近地表
Ingenuity will capture images with approximately 10 times the resolution of orbital images.
机智号 可以捕捉到分辨率约为轨道图像10倍的图像
Ingenuity is pretty lightweight though.
不过机智号 的重量相当轻
It only weighs 1.8 kilograms and has two counter-rotating rotors that are 120 centimeters in diameter.
它的重量只有1.8kg 有两个直径为120cm的反转螺旋桨
It's pretty awesome
很厉害啊
that they can just use to counter-rotating blades to be able to do all the control dynamics of this vehicle.
机智号 只需要一个同轴反桨 就能完成所有控制动力
The little helicopter drone is expected to fly at least five times in its 30 day test campaign
这款小小的直升机无人机预计在30天的测试活动中至少飞行5次以上
with each flight lasting no more than just three minutes.
而每次飞行时间不超过3分钟
While that's not that long of times, of course
虽然这并不是那么长的时间 但当然了
the blades have to do quite a bit of work in that really thin atmosphere.
桨叶必须在那种非常稀薄的大气中做相当多的工作
The idea of there being a drone,
这样的想法
that's just flying around on another planet though, millions of kilometers away,
让无人机在数百万公里之外的另一个星球上飞来飞去
honestly, absolutely incredible to me.
老实说 对我而言感到十分不可思议
Okay. Okay. Okay. I might just be a little bit biased.
好吧 我可能只是有点偏见
Perhaps I just think it's extra cool because I've seen it with my own eyes from only a few meters away
好了知道你亲自见过了
也许是因为我亲眼见过这个直升机 仅仅几米之外 所以感到特别帅
while it was going through its final testing at JPL.
当它在JPL进行最后测试的时候
Now this will just be the first of hopefully many drones to fly around on other worlds.
现在 希望这只是一个在别的世界上飞无人机的一个开端
Because of course, I'm also looking forward to the dragonfly mission,
当然 因为我也很期待蜻蜓号 的任务
but it'll be a quad copter that'll be flying around on Saturn's largest moon Titan.
但这将是一个四轴飞行器 它会在土星最大的卫星土卫六上飞行
but that won't happen until the mid 2030s.
但这要到2030年代中期才会发生
So Perseverance is a pretty massive overhaul of Curiosity and has a ton of cool things to look forward to.
那么毅力号 是对好奇号 的一次相当大规模的改造 并且有一大堆很酷的东西值得期待
So all this said, I asked my friend and JPL engineer Bobak Ferdowsi what he was most excited for.
所以说 我问我的朋友 JPL工程师Bobak Ferdowsi 关于他最兴奋的是什么
Hey Tim, it's Bobak, you know, as one of the people who got to work on Curiosity and help get it to Mars
嘿 Tim 我是Bobak 你知道的 作为一个帮助好奇号 到达火星 并为其工作过的人
with Perseverance kind of being like a 2.0 version of that.
毅力号 有点2.0版好奇号 的感觉
It feels a little bit like a proud grandparent now,
现在感觉我就有点像一个骄傲的爷爷奶奶
and I'm really excited for the mission and what it's going to accomplish
我对这个任务以及它要达到的成果感到很兴奋
and all the improvements that were made from Curiosity.
还有就是从好奇号 中得到的所有改进
I think two that stand out to me in particular: Terrain relative navigation,
我觉得有两个特别突出的地方 地形相对导航
that's basically where the rover can avoid major obstacles during the landing
这基本上可以让漫游车在降落过程中避开主要的障碍物
that really increases the chance of landing safely.
这真的增加了安全着陆的可能性
And I would say the MOXIE instrument where it's creating oxygen on the atmosphere of Mars,
还有一个是MOXIE仪器 它将在火星大气中制造氧气
not only does that mean incredible things for generating fuel on Mars,
不仅仅是说 在火星上产生燃料可以说是不可思议的事情
but as somebody who kind of hopes one day maybe to visit their baby on Mars,
但作为一个希望有一天能去火星上看望孩子的人
I would love to have lost the oxygen when I get there.
我到那儿了以后真是会有点喘不上气儿(所以需要制氧机)
I'm really excited for the team.
我真的为团队感到兴奋
I wish them all a super safe and successful journey.
我希望他们的旅途一切安全顺利
I can't wait to see what this mission shows us.
我迫不及待地想看看这次任务会给我们带来什么
Personally, I think I'm in between Ingenuity the drone and just seeing better images in general,
就个人而言 总体上我看好的是机智号 这个无人机 以及更好的图像
but then again, In-Situ resource utilization.
但话说回来 原位资源利用
That's going to be amazing. I mean, think about it.
这将是惊人的 我是指
SpaceX's Starship will require In-Situ resource utilization in order to get back from Mars.
SpaceX公司的Starship要想从火星上回来 就必须利用原地资源
It has to make its own fuel.
它必须自己制造燃料
It has to make methane and oxygen.
它必须制造甲烷和氧气
So I mean, it's a vital thing that needs to be tested out.
所以 我是指 需要测试这个至关重要的事情
There's just so many awesome things to look forward to on Perseverance.
在毅力号 上 有太多令人赞叹的东西值得期待
I don't know if I can pick a favorite, but what about you?
我不知道我是否能挑出一个最喜欢的 但你呢
What are you most looking forward to?
你最期待的是什么？
What other questions do you have about this mission?
关于这次任务 你还有什么问题？
Maybe you're one of the people has their name on Perseverance.
也许你就是其中一个在毅力号 上有名字的人
Let me know your thoughts or questions in the comments below.
请在下面的评论中告诉我你的想法或问题
But if you have any more questions, you can join me live for this launch,
whenever that happens and the landing,
both of which I will live stream with you all
and help point out all of the exciting things along the way and answer your questions live.
Thank you guys for hanging out with me and my brand new studio space that I'm still working on.
There's still a lot more work to be done.
You'll probably be seeing some different changes in different backgrounds in the future.
I'm still working on quite a bit of things.
And I owe of that to my Patreon supporters for helping me make all of this stuff possible.
Making hardware upgrades,
hopefully better image quality we're shooting in 6k now everybody! I love it.
And I'm just so thankful to be able to take this little,
little hobby of mine and turn it into a career. Thank you to you guys.
So if you want to help me continue to do what I do
or get your thoughts and comments on videos before they come out,
maybe you want to talk in our exclusive discord channel
or join our subreddit or gain access to our exclusive live streams,
head on over to patreon.com/everyday. Astronaut. Thank you guys.
And while you're online,
be sure and check out my web store for new shirts like this.
The awesome future Martian society shirt,
which as mentioned has Mars is atmospheric composition
and gravity and reminder to wear a space suit if you're outside.
But it also has the exact landing coordinates of Starship at its prime A
candidate landing site on Arcadia Planatia, Elon Musk even noticed when I was,
I was wearing a shirt and last time I interviewed him and he goes, "Oh,
Arcadia Planatia, is that your favorite place on Mars? I go,
"I think it is, but really it's your favorite place!
Because this is the prime candidate landing site for Starship" and he just laughed. He's like, "yeah,
that's awesome." So you can get your own awesome shirt or other cool merchandise,
by going to everydayastronaut.com/shop.
And I owe a special thanks to Caspar Stanley from Stanley creative,
for his help, with the 3D animations and 3D renders in this video,
check out his awesome Rocket Explorer app,
or maybe show him some love by supporting his awesome work on Patreon too.
And perhaps you noticed my MOVA globe here on the desk or in the background,
I've had these MOVA Globes for years they're some of my favorite things ever.
They're just powered by light. There's no batteries or anything.
There's a link in the description on where you can get your own.
I promise if you get one and you have it,
every guest that's over is going to be like, how does that work?
They're just going to be mesmerized. They're absolutely incredible. So again,
check the link in the description below to see how you can get yours!
Thanks everybody, that's going to do it for me.
我是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
I'm Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut.
将太空的知识带给地球上的普通人